[{"Year":"2019","Questions":[{"Question":"Which document is sent to credit customers at the end of each month?","A":"Credit note","B":"Remittance advice","C":"Sales invoice","D":"Statement of account","Answer":" D","Category":" Blabla"},{"Question":"In which book of original entry are irrecoverable debts recorded?","A":"Cash book","B":"Journal","C":"Purchases day book","D":"Sales day book","Answer":" B","Category":" journal entries"},{"Question":"In which book of original entry will a trader record an invoice received?","A":"Purchases day book","B":"Purchases returns day book","C":"Sales day book","D":"Sales returns day book","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which one of the following is a reason for offering a cash discount?","A":"Bulk buying","B":"Paying in cash","C":"Prompt payment","D":"Repeat business","Answer":" C","Category":" "},{"Question":"Ben records motor vehicle expenses in the motor vehicle account in error. What type of error is this?","A":"Commission","B":"Complete reversal","C":"Original entry","D":"Principle","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which transaction is capital expenditure?","A":"Disposal of a computer","B":"Installation of air conditioning","C":"Repainting of the building","D":"Repairs to air conditioning","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which one of the following is an accounting concept?","A":"Comparability","B":"Materiality","C":"Objectivity","D":"Understandability","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which statement is incorrect?","A":"Assets = Liabilities + Capital","B":"Capital = Assets - Liabilities","C":"Capital - Liabilities = Assets","D":"Liabilities = Assets - Capital","Answer":" C","Category":" "},{"Question":"What is indicated when a business’s bank statement shows a debit balance?","A":"Bank is a creditor to the business","B":"Bank is a debtor to the business","C":"Bank made payment by credit transfer","D":"Bank received payment by credit transfer","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"In which book of original entry are bad debts written off entered?","A":"cash book","B":"journal","C":"purchases day book","D":"sales day book","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"What would be recorded on the credit side of the purchases ledger control account?","A":"discount received","B":"interest charged","C":"payments to credit suppliers","D":"returns to credit suppliers","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"A sole trader included the purchase of a motor vehicle for private use as a business asset. Which accounting concept has not been complied with?","A":"accruals","B":"business entity","C":"going concern","D":"materiality","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"A trader records the purchase of machinery in the machinery repairs account. What type of error is this?","A":"commission","B":"compensating","C":"original entry","D":"principle","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"A business instructs its bank to make a fixed monthly payment of £50 to its energy supplier. Which method of payment has been used?","A":"cheque","B":"credit transfer","C":"direct debit","D":"standing order","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"In non-profit making organisations which one of the following is the equivalent of the cash book of a profit making organisation?","A":"income and expenditure account","B":"receipts and payments account","C":"statement of affairs","D":"subscriptions account","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"During the year a sports club received subscriptions totalling £2 080, which included £160 received in advance for the next year. At the end of the year £120 was outstanding. Which amount for subscriptions should be included in the income and expenditure account?","A":"£1 800","B":"£2 040","C":"£2 120","D":"£2 200","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"A manufacturing company provides the following information.Closing work-in-progress 6 000, Factory overheads 90 000, Opening work-in-progress 7 200, Prime cost 132 000, What is the production cost?","A":"£220 800","B":"£223 200","C":"£228 000","D":"£235 200","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"Where would a manufacturing company show purchases of finished goods for resale?","A":"appropriation account","B":"manufacturing account","C":"profit and loss account","D":"trading account","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"T Song sells goods for cash. How would T Song record this transaction in his books? Give answer in the format : debit account, credit account","A":"cash, purchases","B":"purchases, cash","C":"cash, sales","D":"sales, cash","Answer":" C","Category":" "}]},{"Year":"2018","Questions":[{"Question":"Which of the following is a primary accounting record?","A":"general ledger","B":"petty cash book","C":"sales ledger","D":"trial balance","Answer":" B","Category":""},{"Question":"Which of the following pairs of accounts always have credit balances?","A":"assets and expenses","B":"capital and income","C":"income and assets","D":"liabilities and expenses","Answer":" B","Category":""},{"Question":"Which of the following is an intangible fixed asset?","A":"bank loan","B":"debtors","C":"goodwill","D":"premises","Answer":" C","Category":""},{"Question":"In which section of a balance sheet will a credit balance on a business bank account be shown?","A":"current assets","B":"current liabilities","C":"fixed assets","D":"long-term liabilities","Answer":" B","Category":""},{"Question":"Which of the following would be regarded as an item of capital expenditure for a motor vehicle business?","A":"purchase of a car for resale","B":"purchase of equipment for business use","C":"repair and redecoration of business premises","D":"road tax and insurance payments for a delivery van","Answer":" B","Category":""},{"Question":"If capital expenditure is treated as revenue expenditure, which of the following will be incorrect?","A":"bank balance","B":"creditors","C":"debtors","D":"net profit","Answer":" D","Category":""},{"Question":"Where should a manufacturing business show the cost of delivering its goods to customers?","A":"appropriation account","B":"manufacturing account","C":"profit and loss account","D":"trading account","Answer":" C","Category":""},{"Question":"In non-profit making organisations, what is the equivalent of a profit and loss account?","A":"income and expenditure account","B":"receipts and payments account","C":"statement of affairs","D":"subscriptions account","Answer":" A","Category":""},{"Question":"What is the purpose of liquidity ratios?","A":"to analyse how profitable the business has been","B":"to assess the level of trading","C":"to indicate the business’s ability to pay its debt","D":"to measure how all the assets contribute to earning profit","Answer":" D","Category":""},{"Question":"Which of the following pairs of accounts always have debit balances?","A":"assets and expenses","B":"capital and expenses","C":"income and assets","D":"liabilities and income","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Where would a trader show trade discount?","A":"cash book","B":"discounts account","C":"invoice","D":"purchases ledger","Answer":" C","Category":" "},{"Question":"A trader records purchases of £250 in his books as £520. What type of error is this?","A":"commission","B":"compensating","C":"original entry","D":"principle","Answer":" C","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which of the following transactions would affect a business’s profit?","A":"sale of a fixed asset at book value","B":"settlement of a business debt with discount","C":"settlement of a business debt in full","D":"transfer of cash to the bank account","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"At the end of the financial year a trader added monies outstanding for rent to the rent amount paid during the year to obtain the total rent for the year. Which accounting concept was being adhered to?","A":"accruals","B":"business entity","C":"going concern","D":"materiality","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"To whom do the reserves in a limited company belong?","A":"creditors","B":"debenture holders","C":"directors","D":"ordinary shareholders","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"Where on a balance sheet would a proposed dividend be shown?","A":"current asset","B":"current liability","C":"fixed asset","D":"long-term liability","Answer":" B","Category":" "}]},{"Year":"2017","Questions":[{"Question":"Which document should a business issue on receipt of returned goods?","A":"credit note","B":"debit note","C":"purchase invoice","D":"receipt","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which type of accounts are found in the purchases ledger?","A":"creditors","B":"debtors","C":"purchases","D":"sales","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Bad debts written off would be entered in which book of original entry?","A":"cash book","B":"journal","C":"purchases book","D":"sales book","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"Where is the balance of the bad debts account transferred to at the end of the year?","A":"profit and loss account","B":"purchases ledger control account","C":"sales ledger control account","D":"trading account ","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which is not recorded on the debit side of a purchases ledger control account?","A":"discount received","B":"interest charged","C":"returns outwards","D":"sales ledger set offs","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"A business decides to include the cost of small items of office equipment as expenses in the profit and loss account. Which accounting concept is being applied?","A":"accruals","B":"business entity","C":"materiality","D":"prudence","Answer":" C","Category":" "},{"Question":"In a manufacturing business, which of the following is a factory overhead?","A":"carriage inwards on raw materials","B":"factory supervisor’s salary","C":"hiring of special machinery","D":"manufacturing wages","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"A manufacturing company provided the following information: Closing work in progress 3 300, Factory overheads 83 000, Opening work in progress 2 600, Prime cost 121 000. What was the production cost?","A":"£203 300","B":"£204 000","C":"£204 700","D":"£209 900","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Tom and Jerry are in partnership sharing profits and losses in the ratio of 3:2. Their, partnership provides a salary for Tom of £5 000 per annum. During the year their net, profit was £25 000.What would Tom’s share of the profit be?","A":"£10 000","B":"£12 000","C":"£12 500","D":"£18 000","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"A business sells goods for cash. What are the entries in the books of the seller?","A":" Debit Credit cash sales","B":" Debit Credit cash debtor","C":" Debit Credit sales cash","D":" Debit Credit debtor cash","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which item would be recorded on the debit side of a sales ledger control account?","A":" bad debts","B":" credit sales","C":" payments from debtors","D":" sales returns","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which transaction would not be entered in a business’s cash book?","A":" purchase of goods from T Patel, paying by cheque","B":" purchase of goods by a customer, paying in cash","C":" purchase of goods from J Walsh on credit","D":" purchase of a new machine, paying by cheque","Answer":" C","Category":" "},{"Question":"A business instructs its bank to make a regular payment of a fixed amount to a supplier. What is this known as?","A":" cheque","B":" credit transfer","C":" direct debit","D":" standing order","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"What is the main purpose of preparing a trial balance?","A":" balance the accounts in the ledger","B":" calculate the amount of profit or loss made","C":" ensure the balance sheet is correct","D":" ensure the arithmetical accuracy of the ledger","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"Which of the following errors would be revealed by preparing a trial balance?","A":" an amount received from J Smith, a debtor, was entered in the account of J Smyth","B":" an invoice received from a creditor was not entered in the accounts","C":" a payment received from a debtor for £321 was entered in the cash book as £231","D":" a payment of £761 to a creditor was not posted to their account","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"A trader always uses the diminishing balance method of depreciation for machinery. Which accounting concept is being applied?","A":" accrual","B":" consistency","C":" dual aspect","D":" going concern","Answer":" B","Category":" "},{"Question":"In the accounts of clubs and societies which term represents their capital?","A":" accumulated fund","B":" bank balance","C":" subscriptions","D":" surplus","Answer":" A","Category":" "},{"Question":"At the start of 2016 a club had subscriptions received in advance of £250. During the year subscriptions totalling £8 300 were received, and a further £345 was outstanding at the end of the year. What amount should appear in the income and expenditure account for 2016?","A":" £7 705","B":" £8 300","C":" £8 550","D":" £8 895","Answer":" D","Category":" "},{"Question":"The following information was provided for the year ended 31 December 2016. Sales\t80 000, Cost of sales\t40 375, Stock 1 January 2016\t5 300, Stock 31 December 2016\t4 200, What was the rate of stock turnover?\t","A":" 4.25","B":" 7.62","C":" 8.50","D":" 16.84","Answer":" C","Category":" "}]}]